<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>career on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in career on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 06:41:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some highlights from 2020</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2021/04/05/some-highlights-from-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 06:41:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2021/04/05/some-highlights-from-2020/</guid><description>My track record of posting here has been pretty poor in 2020, partly because of a bunch of content I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed elsewhere. In general, my guiding principle for posting is to only add stuff I&amp;rsquo;d want to read or cite, e.g., because I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it discussed elsewhere. Well, no one has compiled a meta-post of my public work from 2020 (that I know of), so it&amp;rsquo;s finally time to publish it myself.</description></item><item><title>Software commodities are eating interesting data science work</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2020/01/11/software-commodities-are-eating-interesting-data-science-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 09:22:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2020/01/11/software-commodities-are-eating-interesting-data-science-work/</guid><description>The passage of time makes wizards of us all. Today, any dullard can make bells ring across the ocean by tapping out phone numbers, cause inanimate toys to march by barking an order, or activate remote devices by touching a wireless screen. Thomas Edison couldn&amp;rsquo;t have managed any of this at his peak—and shortly before his time, such powers would have been considered the unique realm of God.</description></item><item><title>A day in the life of a remote data scientist</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2019/12/12/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-remote-data-scientist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 22:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2019/12/12/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-remote-data-scientist/</guid><description>Earlier this year, I gave a talk titled A Day in the Life of a Remote Data Scientist at the Data Science Sydney meetup. The talk covered similar ground to a post I published on remote data science work, with additional details on my daily schedule and projects, some gifs and Sydney jokes, heckling by the audience, and a Q&amp;amp;A session. I managed to watch it a few months ago without cringing too much, so it&amp;rsquo;s about time to post it here.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on remote data science work</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2018/11/03/reflections-on-remote-data-science-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 06:33:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2018/11/03/reflections-on-remote-data-science-work/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been about a year and a half since I joined Automattic as a remote data scientist. This is the longest I&amp;rsquo;ve been in one position since finishing my PhD in 2012. This is also the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve worked full-time with a fully-distributed team. In this post, I briefly discuss some of the top pluses and minuses of remote work, based on my experience so far.
+ Flexible hours</description></item><item><title>Advice for aspiring data scientists and other FAQs</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2017/10/15/advice-for-aspiring-data-scientists-and-other-faqs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 09:15:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2017/10/15/advice-for-aspiring-data-scientists-and-other-faqs/</guid><description>Aspiring data scientists and other visitors to this site often repeat the same questions. This post is the definitive collection of my answers to such questions (which may evolve over time).
How do I become a data scientist?
It depends on your situation. Before we get into it, have you thought about why you want to become a data scientist? Hmm&amp;hellip; Not really. Why should I become a data scientist?</description></item><item><title>My 10-step path to becoming a remote data scientist with Automattic</title><link>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2017/07/29/my-10-step-path-to-becoming-a-remote-data-scientist-with-automattic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirs.github.io/yanirseroussi.com/2017/07/29/my-10-step-path-to-becoming-a-remote-data-scientist-with-automattic/</guid><description>About two years ago, I read the book The Year without Pants, which describes the author&amp;rsquo;s experience leading a team at Automattic (the company behind WordPress.com, among other products). Automattic is a fully-distributed company, which means that all of its employees work remotely (hence pants are optional). While the book discusses some of the challenges of working remotely, the author&amp;rsquo;s general experience was very positive. A few months after reading the book, I decided to look for a full-time position after a period of independent work.</description></item></channel></rss>