<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>marketing on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/marketing/</link><description>Recent content in marketing on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>&amp;copy; [Yanir Seroussi](https://yanirseroussi.com/about/)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;|</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 20:02:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Customer lifetime value and the proliferation of misinformation on the internet</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/01/08/customer-lifetime-value-and-the-proliferation-of-misinformation-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 20:02:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/01/08/customer-lifetime-value-and-the-proliferation-of-misinformation-on-the-internet/</guid><description>Suppose you work for a business that has paying customers. You want to know how much money your customers are likely to spend to inform decisions on customer acquisition and retention budgets. You&amp;rsquo;ve done a bit of research, and discovered that the figure you want to calculate is commonly called the customer lifetime value. You google the term, and end up on a page with ten results (and probably some ads).</description></item><item><title>If you don’t pay attention, data can drive you off a cliff</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2016/08/21/seven-ways-to-be-data-driven-off-a-cliff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 21:34:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2016/08/21/seven-ways-to-be-data-driven-off-a-cliff/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;re a hotshot manager. You love your dashboards and you keep your finger on the beating pulse of the business. You take pride in using data to drive your decisions rather than shooting from the hip like one of those old-school 1950s bosses. This is the 21st century, and data is king. You even hired a sexy statistician or data scientist, though you don&amp;rsquo;t really understand what they do. Never mind, you can proudly tell all your friends that you are leading a modern data-driven team.</description></item><item><title>Is Data Scientist a useless job title?</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2016/08/04/is-data-scientist-a-useless-job-title/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 22:26:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2016/08/04/is-data-scientist-a-useless-job-title/</guid><description>Data science can be defined as either the intersection or union of software engineering and statistics. In recent years, the field seems to be gravitating towards the broader unifying definition, where everyone who touches data in some way can call themselves a data scientist. Hence, while many people whose job title is Data Scientist do very useful work, the title itself has become fairly useless as an indication of what the title holder actually does.</description></item><item><title>This holiday season, give me real insights</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2015/12/08/this-holiday-season-give-me-real-insights/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 06:57:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2015/12/08/this-holiday-season-give-me-real-insights/</guid><description>Merriam-Webster defines an insight as an understanding of the true nature of something. Many companies seem to define an insight as any piece of data or information, which I would call a pseudo-insight. This post surveys some examples of pseudo-insights, and discusses how these can be built upon to provide real insights.
Exhibit A: WordPress stats This website is hosted on wordpress.com. I&amp;rsquo;m generally happy with WordPress – though it&amp;rsquo;s not as exciting and shiny as newer competitors, it is rock-solid and very feature-rich.</description></item><item><title>SEO: Mostly about showing up?</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2014/12/15/seo-mostly-about-showing-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 04:25:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2014/12/15/seo-mostly-about-showing-up/</guid><description>In previous posts about getting traction for my Bandcamp recommendations project (BCRecommender), I mentioned search engine optimisation (SEO) as one of the promising traction channels. Unfortunately, early efforts yielded negligible traffic – most new visitors came from referrals from blogs and Twitter. It turns out that the problem was not showing up for the SEO game: most of BCRecommender&amp;rsquo;s pages were blocked for crawling via robots.txt because I was worried that search engines (=Google) would penalise the website for thin/duplicate content.</description></item><item><title>BCRecommender Traction Update</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2014/11/05/bcrecommender-traction-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 02:29:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2014/11/05/bcrecommender-traction-update/</guid><description>This is the fifth part of a series of posts on my Bandcamp recommendations (BCRecommender) project. Check out previous posts on the general motivation behind this project, the system’s architecture, the recommendation algorithms, and initial traction planning. In a previous post, I discussed my plans to apply the Bullseye framework from the Traction Book to BCRecommender, my Bandcamp recommendations project. In that post, I reviewed the 19 traction channels described in the book, and decided to focus on the three most promising ones: blogger outreach, search engine optimisation (SEO), and content marketing.</description></item><item><title>Applying the Traction Book’s Bullseye framework to BCRecommender</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2014/09/24/applying-the-traction-books-bullseye-framework-to-bcrecommender/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 04:57:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2014/09/24/applying-the-traction-books-bullseye-framework-to-bcrecommender/</guid><description>This is the fourth part of a series of posts on my Bandcamp recommendations (BCRecommender) project. Check out previous posts on the general motivation behind this project, the system's architecture, and the recommendation algorithms. Having used BCRecommender to find music I like, I&amp;rsquo;m certain that other Bandcamp fans would like it too. It could probably be extended to attract a wider audience of music lovers, but for now, just getting feedback from Bandcamp fans would be enough.</description></item></channel></rss>