<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Elasticsearch on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/elasticsearch/</link><description>Recent content in Elasticsearch on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>&amp;copy; [Yanir Seroussi](https://yanirseroussi.com/about/)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;|</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 05:39:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/elasticsearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My 10-step path to becoming a remote data scientist with Automattic</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/07/29/my-10-step-path-to-becoming-a-remote-data-scientist-with-automattic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/07/29/my-10-step-path-to-becoming-a-remote-data-scientist-with-automattic/</guid><description>About two years ago, I read the book The Year without Pants, which describes the author&amp;rsquo;s experience leading a team at Automattic (the company behind WordPress.com, among other products). Automattic is a fully-distributed company, which means that all of its employees work remotely (hence pants are optional). While the book discusses some of the challenges of working remotely, the author&amp;rsquo;s general experience was very positive. A few months after reading the book, I decided to look for a full-time position after a period of independent work.</description></item><item><title>Migrating a simple web application from MongoDB to Elasticsearch</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2015/11/04/migrating-a-simple-web-application-from-mongodb-to-elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 03:53:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2015/11/04/migrating-a-simple-web-application-from-mongodb-to-elasticsearch/</guid><description>Bandcamp Recommender (BCRecommender) is a web application that serves music recommendations from Bandcamp. I recently switched BCRecommender&amp;rsquo;s data store from MongoDB to Elasticsearch. This has made it possible to offer a richer search experience to users at a similar cost. This post describes the migration process and discusses some of the advantages and disadvantages of using Elasticsearch instead of MongoDB.
Motivation: Why swap MongoDB for Elasticsearch? I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few posts in the past on BCRecommender&amp;rsquo;s design and implementation.</description></item></channel></rss>