<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>marine science on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/marine-science/</link><description>Recent content in marine science on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>&amp;copy; [Yanir Seroussi](https://yanirseroussi.com/about/)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;|</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 04:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/marine-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building useful machine learning tools keeps getting easier: A fish ID case study</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2022/03/20/building-useful-machine-learning-tools-keeps-getting-easier-a-fish-id-case-study/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2022/03/20/building-useful-machine-learning-tools-keeps-getting-easier-a-fish-id-case-study/</guid><description>Lessons learned building a fish ID web app with fast.ai and Streamlit, in an attempt to reduce my fear of missing out on the latest deep learning developments.</description></item><item><title>Exploring and visualising reef life survey data</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/06/03/exploring-and-visualising-reef-life-survey-data/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/06/03/exploring-and-visualising-reef-life-survey-data/</guid><description>Last year, I wrote about the Reef Life Survey (RLS) project and my experience with offline data collection on the Great Barrier Reef. I found that using auto-generated flashcards with an increasing level of difficulty is a good way to memorise marine species. Since publishing that post, I have improved the flashcards and built a tool for exploring the aggregate survey data. Both tools are now publicly available on the RLS website.</description></item><item><title>The joys of offline data collection</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2016/01/24/the-joys-of-offline-data-collection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2016/01/24/the-joys-of-offline-data-collection/</guid><description>Many modern data scientists don&amp;rsquo;t get to experience data collection in the offline world. Recently, I spent a month sailing down the northern Great Barrier Reef, collecting data for the Reef Life Survey project. In addition to being a great diving experience, the trip helped me obtain general insights on data collection and machine learning, which are shared in this article.
The Reef Life Survey project Reef Life Survey (RLS) is a citizen scientist project, led by a team from the University of Tasmania.</description></item></channel></rss>