<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>WordPress on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in WordPress on Yanir Seroussi | Data science and beyond</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>&amp;copy; [Yanir Seroussi](https://yanirseroussi.com/about/)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;|</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 06:33:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanirseroussi.com/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on remote data science work</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2018/11/03/reflections-on-remote-data-science-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 06:33:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2018/11/03/reflections-on-remote-data-science-work/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been about a year and a half since I joined Automattic as a remote data scientist. This is the longest I&amp;rsquo;ve been in one position since finishing my PhD in 2012. This is also the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve worked full-time with a fully-distributed team. In this post, I briefly discuss some of the top pluses and minuses of remote work, based on my experience so far.
+ Flexible hours</description></item><item><title>My 10-step path to becoming a remote data scientist with Automattic</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/07/29/my-10-step-path-to-becoming-a-remote-data-scientist-with-automattic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2017/07/29/my-10-step-path-to-becoming-a-remote-data-scientist-with-automattic/</guid><description>About two years ago, I read the book The Year without Pants, which describes the author&amp;rsquo;s experience leading a team at Automattic (the company behind WordPress.com, among other products). Automattic is a fully-distributed company, which means that all of its employees work remotely (hence pants are optional). While the book discusses some of the challenges of working remotely, the author&amp;rsquo;s general experience was very positive. A few months after reading the book, I decided to look for a full-time position after a period of independent work.</description></item><item><title>This holiday season, give me real insights</title><link>https://yanirseroussi.com/2015/12/08/this-holiday-season-give-me-real-insights/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 06:57:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yanirseroussi.com/2015/12/08/this-holiday-season-give-me-real-insights/</guid><description>Merriam-Webster defines an insight as an understanding of the true nature of something. Many companies seem to define an insight as any piece of data or information, which I would call a pseudo-insight. This post surveys some examples of pseudo-insights, and discusses how these can be built upon to provide real insights.
Exhibit A: WordPress stats This website is hosted on wordpress.com. I&amp;rsquo;m generally happy with WordPress – though it&amp;rsquo;s not as exciting and shiny as newer competitors, it is rock-solid and very feature-rich.</description></item></channel></rss>